# SANJA SIMONOVIKJ

sanja\_sss@yahoo.com \( \displaysin\_{\text{sanjass.github.io}} \( \displaysin\_{\text{github.com/sanjass}} \)

Full-stack Data Scientist with 3+ years of industry experience leveraging AI/NLP to drive business value at scale. MEng and BSci alumna of MIT, award winner of IMO (International Math Olympiad), multi-hackathon winner. Looking for the right opportunities in Toronto, ON, including remote roles. Fully authorized to work in Canada.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Master of Engineering, Concentration in Artificial Intelligence Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Engineering Jun 2020 - Jun 2021 Sep 2016 - May 2020

#### INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Indeed
Senior Data Scientist, Metadata and Taxonomy Team
Data Scientist, Metadata and Taxonomy Team

Austin, TX (Remote)
Jan 2023 - present
Jul 2021 - Jan 2023

- Crafting and guiding the implementation of tailored, production-grade AI/NLP solutions for extracting and representing metadata from jobs and resumes powering matching systems across domestic and global markets
- Led a pivotal initiative to transition 8 core markets to a fully AI-powered approach to job occupation metadata extraction with an outsized impact, providing a 10-20% increase in key coverage and quality metrics
- Foundational member of a cross-team effort to create in-house HR domain-specific LLM; curated over 20 HR training and evaluation datasets, guided and tested the implementation of a rigorous evaluation framework
- DSci lead for a company-wide initiative to transform metadata collection and usage in a core market (Japan), owning workstreams requiring creative solutions, effective change management, and inter-team collaboration
- Conceptualized and improved upon numerous human-in-the-loop AI-based workflows, facilitating ongoing model improvement and accelerating the expansion of the occupation Taxonomy in over 12 new international markets
- Advising fellow Scientists, Taxonomists, and Engineers on best practices, automation, and trade-off management

Microsoft - Data Science Intern, Docs ML team, Microsoft Fluid Office Cambridge, MA (Remote), Jan 2021

• Created and optimized lightweight classification models that perform 20% better than a heuristic baseline

**Qualcomm** - Software Engineering Intern

San Diego, CA, Jun-Aug 2019

• Built an AI-powered triaging framework, reducing the team's troubleshooting sessions from hours to minutes

## RESEARCH AND TEACHING EXPERIENCE

MIT EECS Department Graduate Teaching Assistant for a popular ML course (6.036)

Feb - May 2021

Improbable AI Group, MIT CSAIL Graduate Research Assistant - Prof. Pulkit Agrawal Feb 2020 - Jun 2021

#### AWARDS AND PROJECTS

• Indeed Hackathon: Indeed Tweakify (AI Resume Writer) - 1st place track winner

Jun 2023

• Indeed Hackathon: Indeed Rhizome (Social Graph) - 1st place overall, Global winner

Aug 2021

• HackMIT: LabelLearn (Smart Data Labeling), 1st place overall, Grand Prize winner

Sept 2019

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, Java, Javascript, Bash, R, SQL, Julia, Cypher

Technologies: Git, Docker, AWS (S3, EC2, Lambda, CloudWatch, EBS), ElasticSearch, Mongo, Django, Neo4j ML Tools: OpenAI, TensorFlow, TFX, Pytorch, Kubeflow, Streamlit, standard ML packages (pandas, dask, pyspark, numpy, scikit-learn, keras, matplotlib), Jupyter Notebooks, Apache Beam, Apache Spark, Optuna, Langchain Human Languages: English, Macedonian (native), Serbian (proficient), Spanish (intermediate), French (limited)